you guys are lucky you're here for the
most fun entertaining interesting talk
of the day probably who knows I have no
idea I thought it would be fun so quick
question how many of you are familiar
with JSON web tokens just throw your
hands in the air
awesome cool it's pretty good if you're
not by the way don't worry about it
it'll still be fun for you and second
question which is gonna sound a little
weird but how many of you are cool if I
use some swearing tonight just throw
your hands up in the air again great
this is gonna go over a lot better than
my last talk then for sure so i'm
randall and i'm here to talk to you guys
about why JSON web tokens suck and are
all so stupid and this isn't really a
talk so much as it is just like a rant
me getting things off my chest
i've always wanted to do this so now i
have the opportunity and you have to
listen to me now that you're here so
this is fantastic
now i know some of you probably use JSON
web tokens and like them and you came to
this talk because you said well why
would someone be talking [__] about them
for you know 45 minutes right and it's a
valid question and that's why at the
bottom of the screen over here i'm my
personal Twitter account and my
company's twitter account so to get
angry you can feel free to tweet hate at
me during this talk that's fine I don't
mind I have a pretty thick skin I can
take it so do your best now quick
background on me why should you listen
to me well my name is Randall mentioned
that before and I work at this company
called octa and I've been basically
building security tools for web
developers for the last five years in a
row I've been designing authentication
libraries authorization libraries in
Python nodejs and golang those are my
three primary technologies I work with
and then for the last 15 years before
that I've been involved in the security
industry primarily working on operating
system security so that's my background
and today I do a lot of open source
projects in those languages on the
screen now let's talk about what JSON
web tokens actually are just to get
started before we get into the fun stuff
okay that way we all know the same thing
now JSON web tokens are abbreviated JWT
you can also print down so that that
shortened acronym as jot just FYI so I'm
going to use these terms interchangeably
so just so you know
now what does the JSON web token it's
basically JSON data that's been
cryptographically signed and the two
important things that people should know
about JSON web tokens is that they're
not fancy so whenever you read an
article telling you JSON web tokens are
awesome whatever you just have to
realize it's just JSON data it's not
cool it's not fancy it's just plain old
JSON data it's really nothing special in
terms of a protocol and then the second
important thing you should know about
them is that JSON web tokens are not
encrypted so what does that mean well it
means that if I have a JSON web token
with some sensitive data inside of it
and I give it to you or you stored in
the web browser whoever has a copy of
that token can see all the information
you've ever put inside of it so a lot of
people tend to think JSON web tokens are
some security protocol and whatnot that
is not true they're not designed for
this purpose now there is a way to
encrypt JSON web tokens but in almost
99.99% of cases they're not so just keep
that in mind now because we mentioned
cryptographic signatures let's talk
about those what is a cryptographic
signature well think of it like this
let's say that I write a letter so I
type a letter up and I print it out and
then at the bottom of the letter I sign
my name
and I mail it to you when you get that
letter what do you do well you read the
words and then at the bottom you look at
my signature and you know my name
Randall so you see that and you know
what my handwriting looks like and so
you say well hey I trust that this is
Randall because I know what his
signature looks like and therefore I
trust all the information that was typed
up on the page and that's basically what
a cryptographic signature is it's just a
way to verify that some data was
generated by a particular person that's
all cryptographic signing is now what do
you JSON web tokens do well basically
they prove that some JSON data can be
trusted they prove that JSON data is
legitimate essentially and the best way
to describe this in real life the best
analogy is every time you go to the
airport when the TSA asks you for your
identification and you hand them like
your California driver's license they're
gonna look at that they're gonna see
your height your age your weight your
eye color all these different things
about you that's like the JSON data on
your ID card then they look at the
license and they say well it has the
stamp of California on there
and they know what California is they
know what the ID supposed to look like
they know what the watermarks are
supposed to look like and so they trust
that the data on the ID is valid so
tokens or JSON web tokens are basically
passports identifiers things like that
now how do people typically use JSON web
tokens well I can almost guarantee you
most of you are here because most people
use JSON web tokens as identity proof
they used it to log someone into a web
site and manage their identity that's
the main use case that people have
adopted adopted them for today excuse me
and that's what I'm primarily gonna be
talking about now you can use them for
lots of other things but this is the the
big one that people care about now
there's two ways that people use JSON
web tokens for identity both ways are
are pretty normal but the first way the
way I'm describing on the screen right
here is by far the most common this is
what you'll see in almost every website
tutorial blog posts udemy course
whatever is what's on the screen right
here
and let me just walk you through real
quick cuz it's important to know so when
a user logs into your website they
typically go to a login page they enter
things like their email and password and
they hit submit those credentials are
going to get transmitted from your
browser to the web server that's running
the web site the web server is going to
validate your credentials it's going to
make sure your password is correct in
your email scrat's then it's going to
generate a JSON web token for you and
store all of your user information
inside of that token as JSON data so if
your user account has like a first name
a last name a user name birthday stuff
like that that will all be encoded in
this JSON data in the JSON web token
then when the website sends that
response back to the browser that
actually logs you in that information is
going to be picked up and stored inside
of HTML local storage which is just a
JavaScript API that runs in the browser
and it's going to take this token which
is just a big long string and store it
inside of local storage and then from
this point on every time you need to
make a request back to the website from
your browser so like view a dashboard
page review a billing page if you need
to reify yourself if it's a page that
that requires login
you're gonna use some JavaScript code to
pull that token out of local storage and
send it to the website to re-identify
you it's basically like a session that
makes sense to everyone
cool now the second way people use these
things is exactly the same thing I just
described with one minor difference
instead of storing the token inside of
local storage in the browser the token
will be stored inside of a cookie and
cookies we're gonna get into it later
but they're not used for JSON web tokens
very often for numerous reasons which
we'll get into so just keep these in
mind as we go through this now here's
the fun part all right what happens if
you google JSON web tokens anyone know
just shout it out was that hate articles
no actually exactly the opposite
everybody [__] loves JSON web tokens
you guys everybody's in love with these
things there's the million blog posts
YouTube videos tutorials on plural sign
and stuff teaching you how to use JSON
web tokens to log into websites and why
it's the most secure thing and why it's
really cool and fast and efficient and
scalable and all these things and what's
crazy about this is that everyone is
wrong so all these things are completely
inaccurate they are the wrong way to do
it and this is one of the reasons why
security on the web gets such a bad rep
is because most people have no idea what
they're doing and that's okay but it's
also a little funny to me and what I
find particularly interesting is that
even in the security industry amongst my
peers I oftentimes feel like I'm taking
crazy pills because a lot of people will
genuinely love JSON web tokens and it
makes me feel absolutely insane
so my selfish reason for coming here
tonight is really to just sort of like
pitch you guys my idea about why I think
they suck and hopefully get some of you
to agree with me to validate that I'm
not in fact crazy so that'd be fantastic
now the second part of this story is
that it's not really the gist on web
tokens that I hate so much as it is that
I think the real tragedy of this story
is that we have all collectively
forgotten how amazing sessions are in
session technologies and I think that's
the real moral of the story I want to be
telling you tonight is why sessions are
so much better than JSON web tokens in
every single possible way and why JSON
web tokens just fucking's up so that's
the idea
now before we get into all the reasons
and there will be a lot of them let's
quickly talk about some terminology so
we're all on the same page now I
absolutely hate defining terminology but
in this case I want to make it as
pleasant as possible so if you don't
understand something throw your hand up
and ask the question and we'll power to
it now first off let's talk about jots
there's two different kinds of jots that
people use the first one is called a
stateless job this is by far the most
common type of job you will encounter
stainless jobs are what I described
before they're a JSON web token that
contains all of you user information
inside of the JSON data of the token so
if you have an email a first name a last
name in a favorite color those three
fields would be encoded in the JSON web
token as JSON data now how do these work
well let's say you have a user who's
logged in to a website and the user is
wants to view a page on the website so
he says hey let me see this page when he
makes that request he's going to be
sending as JSON web token along to the
website to identify himself the website
when it receives the request is going to
validate this token and what do I mean
by validation I mean it's going to check
this signature and say hey do we trust
this JSON data inside of this token
that's the benefit to that cryptographic
signature stuff we mentioned before then
once it's been validated it's going to
look inside the token and extract of the
JSON data it's gonna say well hey I see
you have an email in here I see your
first name your last name your favorite
color all this data about you I have it
then finally the website is going to
show you a page that you're requesting
maybe a dashboard page or a billing page
and it's going to use your first name
and last name and all those other
variables from the token to render the
page and then display to you and that's
it makes sense right cool now the
opposite end of the spectrum we have a
stateful jar now what is a stateful
jawed it's basically the exact opposite
of a stateless jot okay it's a job that
only contains one piece of JSON data a
session ID and we'll take a look at how
this how this looks right now so in the
exact same scenario the user with a
stateful jot wants to view a page so
what happens well the website is going
to validate the token again
and it's going to extract the JSON data
and see one variable a session ID then
the website is going to talk to some
sort of database now might be Postgres
my sequel MongoDB cockroach DB dynamo DB
local memory could be anything but is
basically gonna say hey we need to come
over here and see where this user is in
our database you're gonna find the user
based on the session ID return the info
to the web server and then finally the
web server is going to render a page and
show it to you this is like your
traditional like server-side web
application does that make sense to
everyone pretty good all right now let's
talk about session cookies so session
cookies is the same sort of technology
except instead of using JSON we're just
storing the session ID on its own inside
of the browser
so there's no JSON web token in this
scenario there's just a session
identifier and let's see how this looks
so the user is gonna make a request to a
website to do your page the website is
going to look at the session identifier
the session identifier is also going to
be cryptographically signed so one
important thing to know about JSON web
tokens is that you know JSON web tokens
are really two things remember they're
JSON data with a cryptographic signature
right a session cookie is just data like
string data with a cryptographic
signature so the only difference between
the two off you know there's a few but
the main difference is that the type of
data that's being used does that make
sense so we're gonna validate the
signature see the session identifiers
talk to the database get the data
exactly like before now you might be
wondering what the difference is between
a session cookie and a stateful jaw
because those two look an awful lot like
one another that's a good question and
I'll tell you what's the same between
both of them right there both
cryptographically signed as I just
mentioned which means we can trust
whatever data we get back from them and
they both contain a session identifier
they contain the same information the
main difference is that again one is
JSON data and one is just a string and
this is really important to understand
everyone following so far cool if you
confuse by the way to shout out
nobody'll alright now next up let's talk
about cookies so I absolutely love
cookies they get a batter rep today but
cookies are pretty cool because they let
you store some data in a browser and
they're basically like the og of like no
sequel so cookies are like the very
original like no sequel database of the
web that's what they are they're built
in 1994 and they basically just store
key value data in a browser and that's
it the only difference between a cookie
and MongoDB is just how much data can
store cookies can store four kilobytes
of data and that's it now okay there's
probably a few other subtle differences
between this and MongoDB but honestly
the end of the day not much basically
the same [__] so remember they only
store four kilobytes of data now how do
we actually use cookies this is
important to know so when a user logs
into your website for instance if you
want to create a cookie so that you can
you can remember who the user is here's
how you do that the user says hey
website let me login the website's going
to log the user in and when the website
sends a response back to the users
browser it's gonna contain the body of
the request right like a thank you
message or whatever or the dashboard
page but more importantly it's gonna
return this header this HTTP header
called set - cookie and the value of
this this cookie is going to be the
cookies name which in this case is
session an equal sign and then the
session ID so like one two three four
five for instance just a random number
that's been cryptographically signs does
this make sense so far this is how you
set a cookie it's just a simple key
equals value declaration inside of an
HTTP header now if you want to create
multiple cookies for instance then you
would just use this header format use
the same exact format and you can say
you know a equals B that's that will
create a cookie called a then you could
create another cookie called C and
assign its value to D so you can create
multiple cookies at once using this
syntax as well and again these are just
HTTP header fields so really really
basic now I do want to take one quick
moment to explain some important
security things about cookies
so cookies on their own are basically
useless unless they have these things
called cookie Flags attached to them
which greatly improve their security now
here's a fun question what's the most
dangerous thing in the entire world for
web security right now the most
dangerous thing in the world is
JavaScript
javascript is the worst okay so running
javascript code inside of a browser is
basically like playing with a gun in
your backpack it's just a really really
bad idea because javascript is an unsafe
language to use it's very hodgepodge
together I know everyone here loves
JavaScript I'm just telling it like it
is right it's sort of a shitty
programming language I'm sorry so we
have to do things to prevent JavaScript
from accessing your your sensitive
information at all costs okay and this
is what some of these cookie flags do so
what cookie Flags should we always tack
on to the end of this HTTP header
declaration well the first one is called
HTTP only this is my personal favorite
because basically what this tells the
browser is hey browser
store this cookie data but never let
JavaScript code access it and I think
that's just amazing because like I said
javascript is super dangerous you should
never have anything to do with it now
the next cookie flag is really great is
the same site flag this helps prevent
something called cross-site request
forgery it's an attack pattern we're
going to talk about it later
but this will help you with that and
finally this gentleman over here
mentioned SSL SSL is definitely
mandatory every time you are doing stuff
that involves sensitive information you
always need to use it and if you add
this secure flag on to your cookie
definitions the browser the browser will
refuse to create a cookie if it was not
set over a secured connection over SSL
so these are all super useful now we
talked about creating cookies let's talk
about reading cookies so once the
browser has a cookie stored inside of it
and the user is using your website
making requests to different pages how
do you is the person building the web
server actually parse the cookie data
out let's talk about that real fast well
basically what ends up happening is
every time the browser makes the request
back to the web site it's going to pass
in this header called the cookie header
now if you notice this is the
same data we had before except the name
of the header is cookie instead of stud
- cookie and in my opinion this is
actually pretty damn sweet this is
pretty nice it's really clear it's
really simple
it just says cookie I mean come on well
what else do you want it's pretty
fantastic and so what do we do well when
we receive a request like this we're
going to parse out the cookie head ever
going to say hey we see this head
recalled cookie we see the data inside
of it we extract we know is separate on
the equal sign we split the string up
and we say this equals this easy super
simple now finally the last term we're
gonna talk about I know this is the
boring stuff bear with me is HTML local
storage how many of you are familiar
with local storage please raise your
hand okay great
well local storage again it's a
JavaScript API that allows you to store
key value data it's basically the exact
same thing as a cookie with two minor
differences difference number one well
three differences difference number one
it can store up to five megabytes of
data instead of four kilobytes of data
so there's a big size differential the
second thing is that local storage only
works inside of JavaScript and then the
third thing is that you need to actually
write JavaScript code to put stuff into
it and take stuff out of it just keep
that in mind we're gonna reflect back on
this periodically so now for the fun
part let's talk about all the myths
about JSON web tokens now these things
have all come from like real world
conversations I've had with developers
over the last three years or so and
these are things I actually hear on a
fairly consistent regular basis so I
thought it would be fun to just debunk
them all one of the time now the first
thing I want to talk about is a lot of
people say that JSON web tokens are
easier to use than traditional
server-side sessions and so let's talk
about that and the best way to talk
about this is to just look at some
history so JSON web tokens the very
first specification for JSON web tokens
was created December 27 2012 so very
early 2013 and basically nobody touched
these things or used them until mid 2014
when the first real blog post was
published about JSON web tokens until
then these
basically completely silent on the
internet so they're only a couple years
old now the next thing to know about
JSON web tokens is that if you've ever
tried to implement them or build out
what I've been talking about here you'll
notice that it's sort of a lot of work
you have to install a JSON web token
library you have to figure out how to
store it inside of the local storage you
have to figure out how to decode the
token and store things inside of it and
validate it and do all these things so
it's not exactly a faultless process now
comparing that to session cookies
they've basically been built into every
single web framework since 1994 and they
have zero effort to use I can't I've
been to a lot of programming conferences
I can't think of a single conference in
my entire lifetime that I've ever been
to where there is a talk about how to
use a session cookie I'm just saying
it's pretty easy so if I was keeping
score of this right now I'd basically
say hey JSON web tokens have score of
zero and session cookies have a score of
1 now here's the thing I actually do
like keeping score stuff I'm sort of a
numbers guy but I'm having extremely bad
short-term memory so what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna say JSON web tokens and I
want you guys to shout 0 come on Jason
web tokens session cookies okay cool
this is not too bad for 5:30 or whatever
time it is now next myth JSON web tokens
are a lot more flexible than sessions
this is an argument I hear quite
frequently when people want to use these
things so let's take a look here is the
JSON web token and what it looks like
this is how you define it just some JSON
data here is a session cookie with the
exact same data inside of it now
remember session cookies are set by
defining HTTP header called set - cookie
you can put whatever information inside
of it you want so between both of these
things there's exactly the same data
stored key value data and so basically
there's no difference right now some of
you who know a little more about JSON
web tokens as I was saying that we're
probably a little frustrated because
you're like wall
yeah that's technically true but that's
not the flexibility we're talking about
Randol JSON web tokens have all these
really cool interesting things called
claims inside of them and that's the
flexibility most people are talking
about when they talk about why they're
more flexible so let's talk
claims inside JSON web tokens are really
nothing more than extra JSON data
embedded in there by default that's
really all of this and JSON web tokens
the spec for it has a bunch of these
things that are defined now I'm picking
two out of this fruit as an example to
show you so here's two claims the first
ones called IAE which is short for issue
dot it tells you when the token was
created as a UNIX timestamp the next one
here is exp which is short for expires
that this is another UNIX timestamp that
tells you when the token actually
expires now these things are really
awesome in JSON web tokens because it
allows you as a developer to say hey
once the seizures logged in their token
their identity is only gonna last for
let's say an hour then they're gonna be
logged out of my website that's pretty
cool but here's the thing that same [__]
has been available in cookies since 1994
again and so everybody's wrong it's not
more flexible it's a lie it's a mess and
so if we go back to the scoreboard we
have JSON web tokens with a score of and
we've got session cookies with a score
of okay next this is another big one
especially in my industry in the
security industry people love these
things because they feel like they're
more secure so let's take a look at the
track record here now Jason web tokens
let's talk about the good first off
there cryptographically sorry from what
we've already discussed about
cryptographic signing it's pretty sweet
it's pretty useful so that's great and
the other thing what's great about them
is they technically can be encrypted
although almost never are but we'll give
them a point for that anyways
on the downside however the spec is
incredibly complicated especially for
implementers building these JSON web
token libraries now I'm not specifically
talking about JSON web tokens here I'm
actually talking about the family of
specifications surrounding it called the
Jose family of specs this includes JSON
web signatures JSON web keys and a lot
of other things and this spec is one of
the most complicated things I have ever
endured in my life so I don't wish it
upon anyone also in the course of the
last two years there's been multiple
massive vulnerabilities found in
basically every single JSON web token
library and so the security track record
is not super fantastic right now it's
still very young early
technology and finally the worst part
about it is that depending on what
programming language you using or what
specific json web token library you're
using there can be a massive difference
in the parity between what algorithms
and what support for different parts of
the spec each library has this is a real
pain point for me because I build a lot
of applications that are partially in
Python partially in JavaScript partially
an NGO or Java things were there's
different languages involved and because
these technologies are still so young
there are very few libraries that
actually supported the entire JSON web
token spec now if we compare this to
session cookies there's only a good
column because basically they are also
cryptographically signed are also
encrypted have been around since 94
there's been zero complexity in the spec
as a matter of fact when I walked you
through those header definitions earlier
of set cookie and cookie that's it right
super basic
there's been no vulnerabilities anywhere
and these things have been built into
every web framework in every programming
language since the beginning of time so
in terms of security cookies have a far
superior track record and so am let's
give them go back to the scoreboard we
got JSON web tokens and session cookies
ok next up how many of you have ever
been on a web site and you see that
little banner at the bottom of the page
it says hey just so you know we're using
cookies to store your information so
click here to confirm whatever anyone
seen that before all right that's the
results of the EU cookie law directive
which was passed back in 2011 it didn't
start getting enforced until 2012 I
believe and basically a lot of
developers think that JSON web tokens
are a valid way to work around this
legislation so you don't need to put
this banner on your web site if you're
building a website for EU customers so
want to talk about this for a second now
the here's the theory that I've heard
people explain to me they say that this
cookie law basically requires you to
display this banner on your website if
your website uses cookies to store
people's information such as their
logging data inside of a cookie things
like that and so the theory is that if
you're using JSON web tokens and you're
storing them in local storage because
that's not a cookie you are no longer
required to comply with this law and
this is the biggest misconception of
them all because it's factually
incorrect
now it's unfortunate
because this law is named the cookie law
it implies that like cookies are somehow
a bad thing but the text of the cookie
law is actually quite specific and
basically what it tells you to do is you
need to put this banner on your site if
you're storing data about the user
that's tracking data something that is
not required for the user to log in so
if you're using Google Analytics or
Optimizely or KISSmetrics or any sort of
third party ad or tracking network code
then you need to put this banner on your
site regardless of where that data is
stored even if it's stored inside of
local storage it doesn't matter you are
required to show this banner and as a
matter of fact fun fact inside of the
cookie law there's actually wording
which says user information used for
logging purposes is exempt so you can
store it as much user information as you
want inside of a cookie and you still
don't need to put this banner on your
site so it's just a bunch of myths so
going back to the scoreboard
we got JSON web tokens with zero points
session cookies with four points pretty
cool so next up this gentleman over here
said earlier cross-site request forgery
is a big issue which it is so let's talk
about that how many of you know what
cross-site request forgery is see a few
hands alright for those of you who may
not be familiar let's do a quick recap
so let's say you have all your banking
done on Bank calm that's what I use for
banking it's great and you're logging in
and you're checking your accounts which
is some pretty typical [__] on a Friday
now next up let's assume that your bank
has a way to transfer money from your
account to someone else's account a
transfer page and on that page is in
HTML form and that form has two fields
one field is the amount of money you
want to transfer and the second field is
the email address of the person you want
to transfer the money to again pretty
common but let's say you have a friend
who's sort of a jerk okay and this
friend's a web developer obviously
because all the jerks in the world are
primarily web developers in case you
didn't know and this friend basically
builds a little web page and on that web
page there's an image tag and the source
of that image tag is actually Bank com
slash transfer question mark
amount equals a million and two equals
jerk at gmail.com and then your friend
sends you a link to this webpage to open
up in slack or whatever right so what
happens when you click this link and you
load up this webpage well I'll tell you
what happens you open the page your
browser parses the HTML it sees the
image tag it looks at the source of the
image tag it issues a get request to
bank.com flash transfer a question mark
whatever whatever you are then issuing
that request from your browser which is
logged into your banking website so you
go to the transfer page and the bank
developers they're not the best so what
do they do they take those query strings
out of the URL and they fill it in as
form inputs then they submit the form so
what happens well basically you've been
tricked by your friend into transferring
a million dollars into his account
that's basically cross-site request
forgery it's a really cheap easy way to
trick people into doing things on a
website that they don't even know
they're doing by the way what happens
after that well your friend definitely
cash it up well the bank is gonna of
course send the money but then your
friend is gonna cash it out for Bitcoin
and leave the country
that's definitely what happens so here's
the myth people say the JSON web tokens
prevent CSRF and let's talk about why
that's not true well I'll shortcut you
I'll tell you the answer real quick it
has nothing to do with JSON web tokens
it basically has to do with where you're
storing sensitive user information so if
you're storing sensitive information
inside of a cookie because cookies are
automatically sent by your browser to a
website basically you always it will be
vulnerable to CSRF but if you store
things inside of local storage like a
JSON web token for instance you've
completely prevented cross-site request
forgery from happening and the reason
why is because again local storage only
works in JavaScript and you have to
write JavaScript code in order to send
that to a website to log you in so an
attacker can trick you into writing
JavaScript code they can only trick you
in to clicking a link and so therefore
you're safe from CSRF but here's the
problem
a lot of people do this and they don't
realize that they've just made
mistake which is that instead of fixing
security problems they actually open
themselves up to a security problem
that's a way way WAY worse which is XSS
otherwise known as cross-site scripting
attacks and so I want to talk about this
for a moment
CSRF is a really easy pattern to fix
this has been known since 1994 when
cookies were first started this has
always been a big popular attack vector
on the web and there's a million and one
ways to prevent CSRF attacks from
happening if you've ever used a
programming web framework like Django or
rails or any of these big frameworks
even Nodin Express there's a way to do
this pretty much by default they all
prevent CSRF attacks it's really hard to
actually do these things so this has
been a salt problem for a long time but
cross-site scripting not so much much
more difficult to prevent now this is
the Twitter bootstrap documentation now
quick show of hands how many of you have
ever built a website where you copied in
like bootstrap C Nia and jQuery CDN view
j/s CDN anything like that raise your
hand now I see there some people not
raising their hands so we got some liars
in the audience because I know you've
all [__] done this before so I don't
want to hear it I know you've done it
don't lie about it it's okay we're not
gonna judge you judgment free zone but
here's the thing that's a that's really
bad news for security and the reason why
is because every time you link to
third-party JavaScript in your site what
happens if that javascript is
compromised okay so if you're hosting
JavaScript code yourself you can usually
prevent compromised what happens if
you're linking to like some shitty
analytics companies javascript code and
their stuff gets hacked and someone
modifies their JavaScript code to
basically run on your website because
you already running it on your website
right so their code runs on your website
and what does it do it grabs everything
stored in local storage including your
JSON web token and sends it off to their
API so they can collect your users
sensitive data that's a really really
bad thing which is almost impossible to
protect against and this happens a lot
by the way so several about six or seven
months ago I was doing responsible
disclosure with this large analytics
company and I reported to them that
their public third-party JavaScript
which is CD end into probably tens of
thousand
of really large websites could be
publicly modified via Amazon s3 bucket
with the right permissions open so this
is actually incredibly incredibly common
this is by far the most common type of
attack on the web today and super easy
to happen now some of you might be
thinking well you know it's actually not
a big deal because if I'm building a
website I just won't use third-party
JavaScript and that's a legit thing like
if you don't use third-party JavaScript
you are safe you can use local stores
all day but here's the thing I pretty
much guarantee you you're unable to do
this and why do I say that well if
you're working in a company you probably
have other people working on your
website usually marketing people or non
developers are gonna be contributing
stuff and what do these people want to
do and want to track users they want to
use Google Analytics no one use
Optimizely they want to use all these
tools which are basically third-party
JavaScript they require you to link out
to their CDN and so you can never really
be safe of this and you don't have to
you don't have to just take my word for
this so wasp
the open web application security
project is sort of the largest internet
security think tank on the web all the
best researchers published there etc etc
and this is a direct quote from their
Docs never store any sensitive
information inside of local stores so
what does this mean to you well this
should mean that if you've ever read a
tutorial telling you to store JSON web
tokens and local storage it was wrong so
you should run away and turn back and
run away never turn back sorry because
it's just bad information and
unfortunately if this information is
widely propagated out there so going
back to the scoreboard
we got JSON web token so the score of
you guys can do better than this come on
and session cookies are the score of all
right have some enthusiasm people [__]
so next next argument for people who
want to use JSON web tokens they say
they're better then they're better for
cross domain authentication so if you're
handling a website with different types
of login across multiple domains this
can be an issue so let's talk about this
let's say you have a public-facing
website dub dub dub website comm and the
user clicks the login button and wants
to be logged in that user
is going to get redirected to login da
website comm because in this example
we're talking cross-domain baby
different domains and what happens then
that long and domain is gonna show you a
login page it's gonna say hey what's
your email what's your password etc so
you as the user will fill in some
information and hit submit and that goes
up to the server the server's gonna log
you in it's gonna create a cookie for
you so you now have a cookie and you're
logged in to log in dot website com then
it's going to generate a JSON web token
and what's it gonna do this JSON web
token is gonna last for 10 seconds and
then this login page is going to
redirect you with an HTTP 302 redirect
to the dashboard domain so now in your
browser you see that you're at dashboard
website com question mark token equals
and then this JSON web token and then
what happens
well this dashboard page is going to see
the token in a query string it's going
to parse it out it's going to validate
the token it's gonna check that
signature and then what it's going to do
is it's going to create a cookie and log
you in on the dashboard domain so now
you have two cookies one on the logging
domain one on the dashboard domain so
you logged into both of these places
right now and JSON web tokens have been
used but not for authentication purposes
they were used to help redirect and
finally now that you're logged in you
are shown a dashboard page and this
pattern here works across anything
subdomains top-level domains as many
domains as you want this is the best
possible way to handle cross domain
authentication while still using cookies
one of the reasons people think JSON web
tokens are better for cross domain is
because cookies are typically bound to a
single domain but following this pattern
works around that issue in a really
convenient and simple way and because we
already know the JSON web tokens can't
be stored in local storage and we know
it's not safe to do that this is the
safest way to use it and this is not
using JSON web tokens for the identity
this is using it for a trusted redirect
now let's go back to the scoreboard JSON
web tokens
Sachin cookies any questions about that
by the way I feel like I lost some
people ah sorry that's what I forgot to
explain he's saying why don't chase on
web tokens get a point here because I
use them well sir I'm talking [__] about
JSON web tokens in the sense that you
shouldn't use them for web
authentication and this is not using
them as identity information this is
using them to have a proven redirect and
secondly I showed them here's an example
of a alternate way to do that although
you could easily have used a
cryptographically sard an identifier
regardless it would have been more
efficient anyways and we're going to
talk about that in a minute
okay good question so next up mobile a
lot of people think JSON web tokens are
better to use on mobile now quick
disclaimer this talk I'm focusing on
JSON web tokens in the context of a
browser like web authentication and
here's the thing this is the easy
someone explained because it's just
patently false and the reason why is
because browsers on a mobile phone or a
tablet work exactly the same as browsers
on any desktop or laptop so it's just BS
BAM JSON web tokens zero session cookies
set up awesome now let's talk about
efficiency so my background is doing a
lot of low-level work C and assembler
and things like that and so I get a
little excited when we're talking about
efficiency
now here's what I do I like numbers so I
built two really simple applications in
one of them I use the node JSON web
token library the most popular one so
you create a JSON web token just like
this it only has one piece of
information a session ID which is a
sporty character alphanumeric string
then what I did is I took the same
cryptographic signing algorithm and I
basically cryptographically signed that
same alphanumeric string just on its own
without a JSON web token and I compared
how big both of these strings are at the
end so the JSON web token is basically
179 bytes and the signed
identifier is only 64 bytes so what does
that mean it means the JSON web token to
carry the same exact information is
roughly three times
larger in the best case scenario now you
might be saying this is miniscule
difference because we're talking about a
small number of bytes here right this is
just a little bit of bytes it doesn't
really matter but here's the thing this
is the best-case scenario most people
when they're using JSON web tokens
they're using stateless jots where all
of your user information is embedded
inside of the token and so what did i do
i went back and i modified the example
to add in some actual user information
from some of the apps that i run and
what did i see that in the real world
tokens are in the best-case another
scenario ten times larger and in average
scenarios seventy-five to a hundred
times larger so it actually ends up
making tokens very large well over four
kilobytes which means they cannot be
stored instead of a cookie
because they're now far too large and
what does that mean it means they then
have to be stored inside of local
storage and what do we know about local
storage that Oh wasp hates local storage
and garbage you just never use it to
store sensitive data and so the point is
going to session cookie so JSON web
tokens now have a square of and session
cookies now have a score of sweet we're
almost done you guys next up people say
JSON web tokens are easy to revoke so
let's say someone compromises your
identity how do you handle it well let's
say you log in and you get back a JSON
web token and you log in to a website
then let's say that someone compromised
your token because you're using local
storage and they start making requests
to the website on your behalf but let's
also say that on your web server you
detect there's something weirds going on
you say hey you know what I'm going to
revoke this token from this user I know
what's compromised so what am I gonna do
I'm gonna change the signing key then
I'm using to create these tokens now
changing the signing key basically means
you're changing your name so if I were
to mail you a bunch of letters then all
of a sudden I change my name
those letters that have my old name on
it you can no longer trust those so what
happens
well you've logged the user who got
hacked out of your website but you've
also logged out every other user on your
website and that's a really shitty user
experience and so it's bad
now I've actually given this talk before
and someone said hey that's actually not
true only a noob would do that what we
do is we use this common pattern called
the token revocation pattern with a
token revocation list and so let's take
a look at that so every time you view a
website if you have a JSON web so again
what a lot of people do in the real
world is they say well you know what I'm
using JSON web tokens but I want to be
secure so every time the user comes and
talks to my website I'm gonna get their
token I'm gonna check it against a
central database or cache that I have to
see if it's move blacklisted and if it
has been blacklisted then I'm gonna kick
this user out of my website but all I
really have to say about that is like
what's up because the main benefit of a
JSON web token is a stateless it
contains all that information so you
don't need to talk to a database or
cache on your back-end and guess what
even if using tokens you absolutely need
to talk to a database your back-end on
your product to prevent this from
happening and so there's zero benefit
except you now storing more bytes in the
browser and necessary and so it sucks so
JSON web tokens now have zero points
session cookies have nine points awesome
we're almost done I know you guys are
getting tired almost there
JSON web tokens are easier to scale a
lot of people think this right let's
take a look at the facts on the good
side JSON web tokens you can check their
cryptographic signature and that they
haven't expired locally you don't need
to talk to a database or any [__]
like that but on the downside this is
only true if you have a stateless job
where everything is embedded inside of
it and it puts a lot of effort on your
user to pass more bandwidth from you
their browser to your website on every
single request session cookies on the
other hand they can be used well on the
server side you can do all sorts of cool
mechanisms to speed it up and things
like that but the downside of course is
they always require some sort of
external database or cache in order to
make it work so these are scaling
arguments now I think we've already
talked pretty significantly about why
you can't use JSON web tokens in most
applications because they're big they
have to go in local sources and know
and all these other facts so I'm gonna
skip re explaining that to prove this
point instead I'm gonna show you the
right way to scale session side back
ends because one of the things I've
learned over the last few years a lot of
people have this this misrepresented
idea about how difficult it is to scale
a session people think scaling sessions
is this really hard thing to do that's
[__] super easy so let's build me
let's say you're building a website and
you have a few thousand tens of
thousands of users a day checking it out
and users are visiting your site well
how do you make this happen whenever a
user visits your site you take their
session ID you check it against your
database to find out who they are and
then you serve the request this will
work just fine
so if you're running a single server a
single database server like postgrads
and [__] or whatever the heck you're
into this works just fine but let's say
your website gets more popular and now
you have a few hundreds of thousands of
users or millions of users what do you
do then well it's basically the exact
same thing except instead of having one
database you horizontally scale and you
have multiple databases and again this
could be postgrads it could be memcache
it could be Redis you can use them in
memory cache to speed this up a little
bit but the concept is pretty much the
same now in today's world this is
extremely easy to deploy so if you're
using Amazon this is like a one-click if
using Heroku it's like one-click if
you're using pretty much any web hosting
provider it's like one click to do all
this and finally what happens when you
get real big when you get to the size of
Google or Netflix or Facebook what do
they actually do they actually do this
so if you have a hundreds of millions of
users you basically I'm cheating a
little bit but what you do is you break
your infrastructure up into different
geographic locations and you have inside
of these locations clusters of caching
servers to store this information in
memory and you make the same thing
happen in a very simple way and this is
how it works in the real world at big
companies this is what they actually do
they don't use JSON web tokens
internally just FYI so going back to the
scoreboard JSON web tokens have zero
points session cookies have ten points
there's one more and this one I'm gonna
cheat a little bit a lot of people think
JSON web tokens were built for security
purposes and so this is me telling you
that is not true like read the history
about them read the spec yourself this
to know what they're meant for people
have bastardized their usage and let me
point out why that is when people log
into a website using a JSON web token
and do bad things right well let's say
you log into a website and your token
expires in an hour but within that hour
you start deleting users and doing
malicious things and so you get you know
your your and basically from the website
they revoke your permissions well if you
keep talking to the website and say hey
let me do bad things then guess what the
website will let you do it because the
benefit of tokens again is you don't
need to talk to an external data store
to validate them you do it locally using
this cryptographic signature and all
these other features and this is a
really bad thing for security so in the
security world there's two things that
are always true it's called the speed
security trade-off so you can either do
things in a secure way where you
validate someone's permission every
request they make or we can do it in an
insecure way which is slightly faster by
just checking things out locally and
caching it and so people need to
understand the JSON web tokens were not
designed for this they were actually
specifically designed for a different
use case now we've covered all the bad
things let's talk about how you should
actually use these things real quick
before we wrap up because you're
probably wondering well what the hell
you know I heard all these great things
about them and I feel a little ripped
off and you're sort of right there's two
use cases I sort of like these things
for so first off is downloading files
let's say you're building a website and
you sell video files or HTML themes or
whatever and you want to sell them to
users so a user goes on your website
they pay for something they want to
download a video well when you click
that download button your website can
generate a JSON web token embed inside
of the token the filename that you're
allowed to download that expires in one
minute and then it will redirect you to
a file server so you can download that
file so if you're on like dub dub dub
themeforest.net you might get redirected
to download dot themeforest.net
with the JSON web token in the URL that
that web server can then just validate
the JSON web token and then let you
download the file
now what's important to note here the
JSON web token is being used a single
time it has a short expiration and it's
never being reused those are the things
that make JSON web tokens useful single
time use short expiration now the the
next use case that's really cool is
password reset functionality so let me
walk you through this so user goes to a
website and says hey I want to reset my
password and so what do you do you say
okay well I'm gonna email you a link to
reset your password and inside of this
email there's gonna be URL to my website
and it's gonna have a JSON web token in
that URL and that token is gonna be
expired automatically in 30 minutes so
then when you go to your inbox and click
that link you're redirected back to the
website with the token in the URL the
website is then going to parse that
token out of the URL and validate it
make sure it trusts that like this is
good and it hasn't expired then finally
it's gonna let you reset your password
this is a great way to use a JSON web
token again because it still sticks to
those two laws it's being used a single
time and has a short duration it's not
being used as identity proof it's being
used for a single time short duration
this is the use case for JSON web tokens
now you might be wondering with all the
hype around them why are they so popular
and this one's actually sort of my fault
so I'm calling out three companies in
particular so one is storm path to
startup that I used to previously
already got the other is off the zero
which a lot of you have hopefully heard
other security companies like my company
and the others octa the company I work
at currently and here's the history of
these things the security industry is
super [__] boring and slow nothing
exciting ever happens like ever it's an
incremental field where things barely
slowly fighting crawl their way to be
interesting over decades and decades of
use in research and so basically nothing
fun that really ever happens for us
that's why we're all bitter and boring
and old
now when JSON web tokens came around
some people basically were thinking
about oh well how can we use them what
can we do this interesting in the
security world instead they said well
maybe we use them to like store session
information and so someone wrote a blog
post about this that blog post got sort
of popping
and people started sharing it around and
basically everyone in the security
industry hopped on this trend and said
well that is an interesting use case
let's play around it and what happened
was that a few companies started doing
this author 0 and storm paths and we all
started promoting these things and what
did we learn well both of our companies
do one thing
we're both API services that operate -
and we basically store users for your
applications so if you're ever looking
for an API service that like handles
user registration login password reset
social log and all that stuff either of
our services will do that for you and
because our articles kept getting
popular and kept gaining views we saw a
lot of new users signing up first
services and so we made a lot of money
off promoting JSON web tokens and so at
the end of the day the reason why JSON
web tokens are so popular today is
because over the last three years both
of our companies strategically use them
as a way to market to developers not
based around any sort of like legitimate
security concerns but purely because
it's a valuable marketing ploy in the
security industry where this stuff is
not happening very often so this is why
they're popular and you can go verify
all this stuff online now what is my
call to action for all all of you today
oh actually sorry one final thing if you
want to verify this online go to Google
in an incognito tab search JSON web
token and look at the first ten results
on Google when I did this the other day
there's one two three four five six
seven of the ten results on the first
page are actually marketing pages
designed to get you to sign up for one
of our two services and give us money
and outsource your authentication needs
okay so I'm not just making this stuff
up now what's my call to action stop
using these damn things okay you don't
need to use them it's easier and more
secure to use session cookies it's way
simpler you won't have to learn anything
they're super awesome I promise nothing
bad ever happened to people using
session cookies and thank you for being
here I know we went over I really
appreciate your time you guys are
amazing and super cool and finally in
the event that you're super insane like
me you can always go get a I hate JSON
web tokens t-shirt on teespring so go
for it if you want just that's why and
thank you I appreciate
[Laughter]